<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Jon Plummer &#8211; Jon Plummer</title>
	<atom:link href="/author/jonplummer_kssjnf/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Today I Learned</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 03:19:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2021/02/jp_round-48x48.jpg</url>
	<title>Jon Plummer &#8211; Jon Plummer</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>What went right in October?</title>
		<link>/2024/11/02/what-went-right-in-october/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jon Plummer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 03:19:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=826</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[So many things, in retrospect:]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>So many things, in retrospect:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Home progress!
<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Landscaping is done, trees are in</li>



<li>Storm drains are cleaned</li>



<li>The network is regularly providing 1200Mbps, after modernizing a bit (paid for by selling the slightly older equipment)</li>
</ul>
</li>



<li>Work progress!
<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>The concept sprint I led was a resounding success – the execs wish they could sell our plan now, but they recognize they need to wait until they fund it and we build it – and there&#8217;s talk of more</li>



<li>The pendulum is swinging back toward being more customer-centric</li>



<li></li>
</ul>
</li>



<li> Life progress!
<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>I pulled 410 last week by doing the plate math wrong, and it was no problem at all</li>



<li>At my last appointment my PT said &#8220;good job;&#8221; I bet PTs don&#8217;t say that often</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Apropos of…nothing (bitcoin)</title>
		<link>/2024/08/01/apropos-ofnothing-bitcoin/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jon Plummer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 15:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=808</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A strategic reserve in (of?) a commodity implies that it’s in the U.S. strategic interest to invest to be protected from price shocks or supply restrictions due to the importance of the commodity to the economy or military readiness. The best way to protect from bitcoin price shock is to not buy any. The best&#8230; <a class="more-link" href="/2024/08/01/apropos-ofnothing-bitcoin/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Apropos of…nothing (bitcoin)</span> <span class="meta-nav" aria-hidden="true">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>A strategic reserve in (of?) a commodity implies that it’s in the U.S. strategic interest to invest to be protected from price shocks or supply restrictions due to the importance of the commodity to the economy or military readiness.</p>



<p>The best way to protect from bitcoin price shock is to not buy any. The best way to protect from a bitcoin supply restriction is to not use any.</p>



<p>Both of these are free.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A quick word about taking feedback</title>
		<link>/2024/07/31/a-quick-word-about-taking-feedback/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jon Plummer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 03:35:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=806</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When receiving feedback on a design or other work the important thing is to see the intent behind the feedback and address that, rather than take the specific advice or try to appease the feedback-giver. Only by addressing the intent behind the feedback can the work be improved. yes, this might mean taking the specific advice, but it might not. The&#8230; <a class="more-link" href="/2024/07/31/a-quick-word-about-taking-feedback/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">A quick word about taking feedback</span> <span class="meta-nav" aria-hidden="true">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>When receiving feedback on a design or other work the important thing is to see the <em>intent</em> behind the feedback and address that, rather than take the <em>specific</em> advice or try to <em>appease</em> the feedback-giver.</p>



<p>Only by addressing the intent behind the feedback can the work be improved. yes, this might mean taking the specific advice, but it might not. The specific advice may not be the right answer.</p>



<p>Appeasement is waste.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Weekly wins for the week of 2024 07 15</title>
		<link>/2024/07/21/weekly-wins-for-the-week-of-2024-07-15/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jon Plummer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 23:29:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=804</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Vacations are winding down and people are starting to come back to work. The team is filling out again.</li>



<li>I convinced the SVP of Product to be quizzed about our product strategy – we&#8217;ll put a script and some visuals together for our annual Company Connect and hopefully address longstanding complaints that people aren&#8217;t sure how their work contributes to our strategy. This has raised other interesting topics that might also become topics, like how we really make money and where it goes, how our pricing and packaging works, etc. A lot of the things I was hoping to accomplish this year have been deprioritized (rightly) due to some technical pickles we find ourselves in, so this represents an opportunity to be influential beyond the usual process sand product stuff we do on the reg; fingers crossed.</li>



<li>The ladies are back and the house is no longer empty. This also means my diet will improve – bachelor-mode Jon is (far) less disciplined than husband-mode Jon.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Weekly wins for the weeks of 2024 07 01 and 08</title>
		<link>/2024/07/14/weekly-wins-for-the-weeks-of-2024-07-01-and-08/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jon Plummer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2024 22:09:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=801</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Small quality-of-life adjustments can have an amazing effect. Sure, the fact that you need to push on the door a little bit to lock its deadbolt is not a huge deal; it hardly slows you down, takes little effort, and there&#8217;s nearly no additional wear-and-tear as a result. Not a huge deal once, that is.&#8230; <a class="more-link" href="/2024/07/14/weekly-wins-for-the-weeks-of-2024-07-01-and-08/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Weekly wins for the weeks of 2024 07 01 and 08</span> <span class="meta-nav" aria-hidden="true">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Small quality-of-life adjustments can have an amazing effect. Sure, the fact that you need to push on the door a little bit to lock its deadbolt is not a huge deal; it hardly slows you down, takes little effort, and there&#8217;s nearly no additional wear-and-tear as a result. Not a huge deal <em>once</em>, that is. Eight times a day every day as people come and go, sometimes with full hands or in a hurry, adds up to thousands of exactly-repeated minor annoyances per year with a single cause that is readily fixed. So the value of that fix is quite high, even if each incident is barely noticeable.</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>I adjusted the strike plates on our exterior doors as mentioned above. It&#8217;s fab!  (Ordinarily this would have been done by the contractor, but I put in the strikes so it fell to me.) Therese were not the strikes with the tab with the screwdriver hole, either.</li>



<li>I also some moved boxes and furniture out of the garage, and rearranged some things, so that we can now park one car in the garage. Halfway there!</li>



<li>During that process I started a tool donation box. There are some things that I&#8217;ve bought two or three times, and some things I have that I hope never to use again, and these can go to the tool library. Fish tape, transfer pump, redundant pipe wrench? Sayonara.</li>



<li>Adapting to people being out for summer trips (and to the recent upheaval in priorities) has not been as difficult as I expected, and it has been fun to dive into a little bit of design work to keep things moving for a team who has both designers out.</li>



<li>I had a delightful coffee with a former coworker who is looking for work. We&#8217;ve resolved to meet quarterly.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Weekly wins for the week of 2024 06 24</title>
		<link>/2024/06/30/weekly-wins-for-the-week-of-2024-06-24/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jon Plummer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2024 23:44:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=795</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Work was…fine…this week. Lots of folks are out or about to be out and while there&#8217;s a moment to try to wrestle projects and processes into shape there are not a lot of people to do that with; preparing projects to to bowl along while they are out is more pressing. But with the girl&#8230; <a class="more-link" href="/2024/06/30/weekly-wins-for-the-week-of-2024-06-24/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Weekly wins for the week of 2024 06 24</span> <span class="meta-nav" aria-hidden="true">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Work was…fine…this week. Lots of folks are out or about to be out and while there&#8217;s a moment to try to wrestle projects and processes into shape there are not a lot of people to do that with; preparing projects to to bowl along while they are out is more pressing. But with the girl and the lady out of the house I was productive with home projects. In the last week I&#8217;ve</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>sent a care package</li>



<li>taken care of a library fine by finding and returning the book</li>



<li>bought a copy of that same book, as a gift</li>



<li>set up garage shelves and populated them</li>



<li>moved the last of the boxes and tools from the neighbors&#8217; garage</li>



<li>set up a greenhouse (shh, it&#8217;s a surprise)</li>



<li>reconnected with an old friend</li>



<li>thrilled a nephew with birthday gifts</li>



<li>installed missing trim on a piece of furniture</li>



<li>installed a door stop on the door to the cat litter box area</li>



<li>went to a baseball game</li>



<li>had the tires replaced on a car that sorely needed it</li>



<li>replaced wipers on that same car</li>



<li>replaced antenna garnish on that same car</li>



<li>washed a different car</li>



<li>given myself a haircut</li>



<li>put a hook on the back of the closet door</li>



<li>built a credible trashcan of an unusual size for a specific installation</li>



<li>found and replaced a furnace filter</li>



<li>epoxied together the house numbers and their holding shape</li>



<li>done some emergency laundry</li>



<li>kept all the plants and cats alive</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Weekly wins for the week of 2024 06 17</title>
		<link>/2024/06/22/weekly-wins-for-the-week-of-2024-06-17/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jon Plummer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2024 22:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=790</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Juneteenth National Independence Day was this last Wednesday. It was odd to have a holiday mid-week but]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Juneteenth National Independence Day was this last Wednesday. It was odd to have a holiday mid-week but</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Juneteenth is worth celebrating, worth remembering, worth considering in this political moment.</li>



<li>I forgot that most of our walls are backed by plywood, so a towel bar installation I had put off was unexpectedly quick and dust-free.</li>



<li>The newish head of engineering thanked me for my attention and care to our common (and coming) process fixes.</li>



<li>The notion that we should (and that it makes economic sense to) focus on the things we can do that will help a lot of (and a lot of new) customers is starting to sink in among influential people. The notion that we should (and that it makes economic sense to) work a little harder so that our customers don&#8217;t have to is taking a little more time, but I think we&#8217;ll get there.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Weekly wins…of late</title>
		<link>/2024/06/15/weekly-winsof-late/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jon Plummer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 19:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=785</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I fell off the weekly wins wagon hard in November, then wrote just one earlier this month. Time to get back on.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>I fell off the weekly wins wagon <em>hard</em> in November, then wrote just one earlier this month. Time to get back on.</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Social win – I saw a friend and past coworker who lives in town and it was lovely. I should reach out to more folks.</li>



<li>Social win – the parents and mother-in-law were in town for the girl&#8217;s graduation, and brought their attendant challenges, but everything went just fine.</li>



<li>Social win – a different friend and past coworker who lives all the way across the country and I have agreed to chat monthly. No reason not to!</li>



<li>Lesson – plan, then check. When I&#8217;ve done just one or the other things have usually gone fine, but not always. This time a stainless steel part about 50mm square ($60 worth of material and cutting) was cut too large and is useless. Turns out it was my fault; all the other parts from the job are fine, I just missed double-checking the dimensions on the one piece. So I need to have that one redone. But the nice people at the fab have agreed to give my reorder special attention.</li>



<li>Leadership – I was able to take a work maneuver, reasserting focus on the goal, and use it with our HVAC subcontractor. &#8220;<em>There&#8217;s no explanation for water appearing there!</em>&#8221; &#8220;Ah, but water <strong>is</strong> there, and got there <strong>somehow</strong>, so there <strong>is</strong> an explanation. I don&#8217;t care whose fault it is, I&#8217;d like to know <strong>how</strong> it got there and what we need to do to prevent it now that this has happened.&#8221;</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A little tip I wish was unnecessary</title>
		<link>/2024/06/14/a-little-tip-i-wish-was-unnecessary/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jon Plummer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 04:24:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=783</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Whenever you are on an online or text chat with tech support of any kind, keep a copy of everything you write in a text file. That way you can repeat yourself (as you inevitably will) with minimal effort. As you think of better ways to explain yourself you can update the note.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Whenever you are on an online or text chat with tech support of any kind, keep a copy of everything you write in a text file. That way you can repeat yourself (as you inevitably will) with minimal effort. As you think of better ways to explain yourself you can update the note.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Recent wins as of 2024 06 02</title>
		<link>/2024/06/02/recent-wins-as-of-2024-06-02/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jon Plummer]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2024 17:51:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=781</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It&#8217;s been a bit since I did a &#8220;weekly wins&#8221; post, mostly because of…lassitude…but with the convenient excuse that we&#8217;ve been finishing the house project and moving and setting up and shepherding the girl through the last bits of high school. So some wins have occurred since the last post, the highest of which have&#8230; <a class="more-link" href="/2024/06/02/recent-wins-as-of-2024-06-02/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Recent wins as of 2024 06 02</span> <span class="meta-nav" aria-hidden="true">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>It&#8217;s been a bit since I did a &#8220;weekly wins&#8221; post, mostly because of…lassitude…but with the convenient excuse that we&#8217;ve been finishing the house project and moving and setting up and shepherding the girl through the last bits of high school. So some wins have occurred since the last post, the highest of which have been</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>High school is done, with great results. Good grades, an IB diploma, grandparents visiting, relief and happiness and the bittersweet knowledge that for some friendships this might be the last hurrah all in one.</li>



<li>We&#8217;re in the house and it is great.</li>



<li>We got our full security deposit back with no argument, probably because we cleaned the hell out of the old place. And because the owners are nice. And because since they plan to move in the management company was losing the business anyway and it </li>



<li>I have an employee that has gotten some negative feedback; the core of it is old complaints, transmitted up the chain of command and lingering. People not working directly with the employee have formed persistent opinions that aren&#8217;t accurate. How to extinguish the senior management echo of a problem that&#8217;s been dealt with? Generate some data – survey the people the employee actually works with to monitor whether or not the positive behaviors in question are witnessed or not. Happily, the employee is taking it seriously, the team members are participating and helpful, and the numbers look good.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
